MICHAEL DEITZ

Winder GA • (470) 403-5100 • Michaeladeitz89@gmail.com

Professional Summary

As a detail-oriented software/hardware technician with over 8 years of experience, and a veteran of the US Air Force, I have honed my skills in supporting and troubleshooting technical equipment, including software upgrades, and delivering exceptional customer support. In addition to my technical expertise, I am highly adaptable to organizational changes and always maintain a positive attitude with a team-oriented approach to problem-solving. I am constantly learning new technologies and applying new knowledge to my work.

KEY SKILLS

Documentation | Team leadership | Active directory | Problem-solving | Microsoft365 | Service now PowerShell |

Google IT Support Professional Certificate

Credential ID: ETY9K9VDWGCB

April – 2022

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science April 2023

Southern New Hampshire University

GPA: 3.89

- Uploaded Angular applications to an S3 bucket and enabling static websites.
- Tested and created functions in Lambda with JavaScript and JSON formatting.
- Created REST APIs for angular applications to handle requests through the lambda functions.
- Deployed APIs with updated URLs.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Triage Analyst

July 2023 – Current

Pearl Insurance Remote

- Assist with systems security for assigned systems as directed by ITS Management.
- Serve as a liaison between the development team and the business to communicate regarding tickets.
- Track and assign tickets according to capacity for each area.
- Facilitate status meetings to review progress & status of open tickets.
- Assist developers with issues, concerns, and eliminating blockers to keep tickets moving along.

Customer Support

January 2021 – May 2023

PaceOMatic Hybrid

- Effectively maintaining queues and working dashboards to answer customers on a timely basis.
- Excellent interactive and communication capabilities, both written and verbal, especially in customer-facing roles
- Answering to inbound questions and requests from prospective and current customers over online live chat, e-mail, and (much less frequently) by phone
- Utilized Jira to plan, track, and manage my projects.
- Ability to work with customers at all levels of technical expertise and provide accordingly support.

Technical Support Manager

August 2018 – January 2021

SNB Amusements Norcross, GA

- Upgraded hard drives, monitors, printers, and other peripherals.
- Performed Functionality tests on newly installed hardware and software.
- Monitored automated messages and responded to alerts with trouble ticketing system ServiceNow.
- Expertly manage technical support operations, diligently troubleshot issues to identify root causes and prevent recurrence.
- Specialized in active directory resetting passwords and accounts.
- Constructed virtual machines with software to test for customer issues with Microsoft Azure.

Technical Support

February 2014 – July 2018

JKH Amusements Doraville, GA

- Served more than 10 customers daily, aided in locating products, and finalized sale transactions.
- Met and exceeded customer satisfaction goals month after month with a CSAT score of 92.
- Handled customer returns and complaints with patience and attention to detail.
- Upgraded POS systems with TeamViewer Also upgraded System software.
- Operated SharePoint to Write down tickets and keep track of issues.

United States Airforce Reserves

March 2010 - July 2016

Structural Apprentice

- Knowledge of building maintenance and construction.
- Fabricated and repaired components of buildings, utility systems, and real property equipment.
- Troubleshot, repaired, and installed commercially manufactured locking devices such as keyed, combinations, ciphers, panic hardware/exit devices, and padlocks.
- Submitted and reviewed supply and equipment requisitions.
- Discussed inspection findings and recommended corrective action.